window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Theory_of_Computation - Regular_Language — Slot 2 (20 Questions)",
  "duration": 55,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Regular_Language — Slot 2",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>If \\(L_{1}=\\{a^{n}|n\\geq 0\\}\\) and \\(L_{2}=\\{b^{n}|n\\geq 0 \\}\\), Consider <br>(I) \\(  L_{1}\\cdot L_{2}\\)  is a regular language <br> (II) \\( L_{1} \\cdot L_{2}= \\{a^{n}b^{n}|n \\geq 0\\}\\)<br> Which one of the following is CORRECT? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Only (I)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only (II)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both (I) and (II)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Neither (I) nor (II)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Only (I)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1971/gate2014-2-15#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following is TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>The language L = {\\(a^{n}b^{n}\\geq 0\\)} is regular</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>The language L = {\\(a^{n}\\)| n is prime} is regular</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>The language L={ w | w has 3k +1    b's for some k \\(\\in\\) N with \\(\\Sigma\\) = {a,b} } is regular.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>The language L = { ww| w\\(\\in \\Sigma^{*}\\) with \\(\\Sigma\\)={0,1}} is regular.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>The language L={ w | w has 3k +1    b's for some k \\(\\in\\) N with \\(\\Sigma\\) = {a,b} } is regular.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1781/gate2014-1-15#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Consider the languages \\(L_{1}=\\phi \\) abd \\(L_{2}=\\{a\\}\\). Which one of the following represents \\(L_{1} L_{2}^{*} \\cup L_{1}^{*}\\)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\{ \\epsilon \\}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\phi\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(a^{*}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\{ \\epsilon ,a \\}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(\\{ \\epsilon \\}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1417/gate2013-8#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Given the language L = {ab, aa, baa}, which of the following strings are in L*? <br>\n1) abaabaaabaa <br>\n2) aaaabaaaa <br>\n3) baaaaabaaaab <br>\n4) baaaaabaa <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2012)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1, 2 and 3</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>2, 3 and 4</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1, 3 and 4</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>1, 2 and 4</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>1, 2 and 4</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1609/gate2012-25#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Let P be a regular language and Q be a context free language such that Q \\(\\subseteq\\)\nP.\n(For example, let P be the language represented by the regular expression p*q*\nand Q be \\(\\{p^{n}q^{n}|n\\in N\\}\\) Then which of the following is ALWAYS regular? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2011)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(P\\cap Q\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>P-Q</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\sum *-P\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\sum *-Q\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(\\sum *-P\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3429/gate2011-24#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>S\\(\\rightarrow\\)aSa|bSb|a|b;  The language generated by the above grammar over the alphabet {a,b} is the set of <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2009)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>All palindromes.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>All odd length palindromes.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Strings that begin and end with the same symbol</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>All even length palindromes.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>All odd length palindromes.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1304/gate2009-12#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following languages is (are) non-regular?<br>\n\\(L_1 = \\{0^m1^n \\mid 0 \\leq m \\leq n \\leq 10000\\}\\)<br>\n\\(L_2 = \\{w \\mid w\\) reads the same forward and backward\\(\\}\\)<br>\n\\(L_3 = \\{w \\in \\{0, 1\\} ^* \\mid w\\) contains an even number of 0's and an even number of 1's\\(\\}\\)<br> <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(L_2\\) and \\(L_3\\) only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(L_1\\) and \\(L_2\\) only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(L_3\\) only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(L_2\\) only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(L_2\\) only</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3345/gate2008-it-35\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following are regular sets? <br><br> \\(I.  \\{a^{n}b^{2m}|n\\geq 0,m\\geq 0\\}  \\)<br> II. \\( \\{a^{n}b^{m}|n=2m\\}  \\)<br> III.  \\(\\{a^{n}b^{m}|n\\neq m\\}  \\)<br> IV. \\(\\{xcy|x,y,\\in  \\{a,b\\}^*\\}\\) <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I and IV only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I and III only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>I only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>IV only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>I and IV only</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/476/gate2008-53#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following languages is regular? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>{\\({ww^{R}|w \\in \\{0,1\\}^{+}}\\)}</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>{\\({ww^{R}x|x,w \\in \\{0,1\\}^{+}}\\)}</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>{\\({wxw^{R}|x,w\\in \\{0,1\\}^{+}}\\)}</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>{\\({xww^{R}|x,w\\in \\{0,1\\}^{+}}\\)}</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>{\\({wxw^{R}|x,w\\in \\{0,1\\}^{+}}\\)}</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1229/gate2007-31#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Let L be a regular language. Consider the constructions on L below:<br>\nI. \\(\\text{repeat} (L) = \\{ww \\mid w \\in L\\}\\)<br>\nII. \\(\\text{prefix} (L) = \\{u \\mid \\exists v : uv \\in L\\}\\)<br>\nIII. \\(\\text{suffix} (L) = \\{v \\mid \\exists u: uv \\in L\\}\\)<br>\nIV. \\(\\text{half} (L) = \\{u \\mid \\exists v: | v | = | u | \\text{ and } uv \\in L\\}\\)<br>Which choice of L is best suited to support your answer above? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\((a + b)^*\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(\\{\\epsilon, a, ab, bab\\}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\((ab)^*\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(\\{a^nb^n \\mid n \\geq 0\\}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\((a + b)^*\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3637/gate2006-it-81\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Let L be a regular language. Consider the constructions on L below:<br>\nI. \\(\\text{repeat} (L) = \\{ww \\mid w \\in L\\}\\)<br>\nII. \\(\\text{prefix} (L) = \\{u \\mid \\exists v : uv \\in L\\}\\)<br>\nIII. \\(\\text{suffix} (L) = \\{v \\mid \\exists u: uv \\in L\\}\\)<br>\nIV. \\(\\text{half} (L) = \\{u \\mid \\exists v: | v | = | u | \\text{ and } uv \\in L\\}\\)<br>Which of the constructions could lead to a non-regular language?<br> <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Both I and IV</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only 1</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Only IV</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Both II and III</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Only 1</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3624/gate2006-it-80\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following statements about regular languages is NOT true ? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Every language has a regular superset</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Every language has a regular subset</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Every subset of a regular language is regular</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Every subset of a finite language is regular</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Every subset of a regular language is regular</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3569/gate2006-it-30\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>If s is a string over (0+1)*, then let \\(n_0 (s)\\) denote the number of 0's in s and \\(n_1 (s)\\)\nthe number of 1's in s. Which one of the following languages is not regular? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>L = {s \\(\\in\\) (0+1)* | \\(n_0 (s)\\) is a 3-digit prime}</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>L = {s \\(\\in\\) (0+1)* | for every prefix s' of s,  |\\(n_0 (s') - n_1 (s')\\)| \\(\\leq\\) 2}</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>L = {s \\(\\in\\) (0+1)* |\\(n_0 (s) - n_1 (s)\\)| \\(\\leq\\) 4}</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>L = {s \\(\\in\\) (0+1)* | \\(n_0(s)\\) mod 7 = \\(n_1(s)\\) mod 5 = 0}</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>L = {s \\(\\in\\) (0+1)* |\\(n_0 (s) - n_1 (s)\\)| \\(\\leq\\) 4}</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/992/gate2006-29#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>A language L satisfies the Pumping Lemma for regular languages, and also the Pumping Lemma for context-free languages. Which of the following statements about L is TRUE? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2005)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>L is necessarily a regular language.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>L is necessarily a context-free language, but not necessarily a regular language.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>L is necessarily a non-regular language.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3787/gate2005-it-40\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following statements is false? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1998)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Every finite subset of a non-regular set is regular</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Every subset of a regular set is regular</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Every finite subset of a regular set is regular</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>The intersection of two regular sets is regular</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Every subset of a regular set is regular</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1678/gate1998-2-6\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 16,
          "question": "<p>Let \\(L \\subseteq \\Sigma^*\\) where \\(\\Sigma = \\left\\{a,b \\right\\}\\). Which of the following is true? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1996)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(L = \\left\\{x \\mid x \\text{ has an equal number of } a\\text{'s and }b\\text{'s}\\right \\}\\) is regular</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\(L = \\left\\{a^nb^n \\mid n \\geq 1\\right \\}\\) is regular</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(L = \\left\\{x \\mid x \\text{ has more number of }a\\text{'s than }b\\text{'s}\\right \\}\\) is regular</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(L = \\left\\{a^mb^n \\mid m \\geq 1, n \\geq 1 \\right \\}\\) is regular</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(L = \\left\\{a^mb^n \\mid m \\geq 1, n \\geq 1 \\right \\}\\) is regular</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2714/gate1996-1-10\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 17,
          "question": "<p>Let \\(\\Sigma=\\left\\{0,1\\right\\}, L = \\Sigma^* \\text{ and } R=\\left\\{0^n1^n \\mid n \\gt 0\\right\\}\\) then the languages \\(L \\cup R\\) and R are respectively <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1995)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>regular, regular</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>not regular, regular</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>regular, not regular</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>not regular, not regular</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>regular, not regular</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/2637/gate1995-2-24\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 18,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following languages :<br>\nL1 = {ww| w\\(\\in\\) {a,b}*}<br>\nL2 = {w\\(w^{R}| \\) w\\(\\in\\) {a,b} *, \\(w^{R}\\) is the reverse of w} <br>\nL3 = {\\(0^{2i}\\)|  i is an integer}<br>\nL4 ={\\(0^{{i}^{2}}\\) | i is an integer} <br>\nWhich of the languages are regular ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Only L1 and L2</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only L2, L3 and L4</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Only L3 and L4</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Only L3</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Only L3</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/724/gate2001-2-6#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 19,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following two statements : <br>\nS1: {\\(0^{2n}|n\\geq 1|\\)} is a regular language <br>\nS2 : {\\(0^{m}1^{n}0^{m+n}|m\\geq 1 and n\\geq 1|\\)} is a regular language <br>\nWhich of the following statements is correct? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2001)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Only S1 is correct</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Only S2 is correct</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both S1 and S2 are correct</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of S1 and S2 is correct</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Only S1 is correct</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/697/gate2001-1-4#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 20,
          "question": "<p>Choose the correct alternatives (more than one may be correct) and write the corresponding letters only:<br>Which of the following is the strongest correct statement about a finite language over some finite alphabet \\(\\Sigma\\)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 1991)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>It could be undecidable</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>It is Turing-machine recognizable</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>It is a context sensitive language.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>It is a regular language.</p>",
            "<b>E.</b> <p>None of the above,</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>It is Turing-machine recognizable</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/528/gate1991-03-xiv\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
